Finding Aid for Washtenaw County Historical Society records, 1827-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Photographs
  - Individuals, 3 folders
    - Reighard, Paul (Box 5)
    - Richmond, Charles H. (Box 5)
    - Rogers, Henry W. (Box 5)
    - Rumsey, Minerva (Box 5)
    - Swathel, John T. (Box 5)
    - Tuthill, Job (Box 5)
    - Tyler, Moses Coit (Box 5)
    - Van Hoosen, Bertha (Box 5)
    - Ward, Henry B. (Box 5)
    - Wells, Ebenezer B. (Box 5)
    - Whitaker, Herschel (Box 5)
    - Wiedersheim, R. (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Negatives (Box 5)
  - Unidentified groups (Box 5)
  - Unidentified females and groups (cabinet size) (Box 5)
  - Unidentified males and groups (cabinet size) (Box 5)
  - Unidentified individuals, cartes de visite (Box 5)
  - Unidentified houses, bridges, and other buildings (Box 5)
  - Unidentified views (Box 5)
  - University of Michigan buildings (Box 5)
  - University of Michigan miscellaneous (including laboratories) (Box 5)
  - University of Michigan stereocards (Box 5)
  - Western camping trip (Box 5)
  - Early forms, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Ambrotypes (Box 6)
  - Ambrotypes (Lucy and Volney Chapin) (Box 6)
  - Daguerreotypes (Box 6)
  - Glass photograph (Box 6)
  - Tintypes (Box 6)
- Glass slides, 53 slides; 1 boxes
  (the following identifications and descriptions were prepared by Lela Duff in 1956)
  - Ann Arbor (slides 1-30)
    - 1. John Allen's home in Virginia (Box 6)
    - 2. Ann Arbor from Hiscock Hill, NW of city 1852 (Box 6)
    - 3. Old Cat Hole, and Mosley House, 12th Street, taken from east? Before Ann Arbor High School? (Box 6)
    - 4. Old Court House (Box 6)
    - 5. Court House Square, Sunday, April 14, 1861. News of firing on Fort Sumter (Box 6)
    - 6. Broadway buildings put up by Anson Brown. Was post office in 1833. Brown died the next year and the post office was brought back to the "old town" on the hill by Thayer who knew prospects of the University. (Box 6)
    - 7. Washtenaw Hotel, Broadway, built 1831 or 1832. Supposedly the finest hotel between Detroit and Jackson; condemned in 1921 (Box 6)
    - 8. Unity Block, SW corner Ann and Fifth Avenue. The First Methodist Church built 1831-1832 sold to Unitarians who worshipped there from 1867 to 1882. Torn down ca. 1930. (Box 6)
    - 9. First Methodist parsonage. (Box 6)
    - 10. Old Fire Engine House. Torn down in 1882. Stephenson states that between 1836, 1838 two engine houses were built; he does not say where. (Box 6)
    - 11. William S. Maynard home on South Main, now the Elk's Club House. Had beautiful, extensive grounds, summerhouses, peacocks. Built ca. 1844. (Box 6)
    - 12. Chapin home, corner of Fourth Avenue and Ann Street. Subsequently Joe Parker's restaurant, Catalpa Inn, and Peters Hotel (Box 6)
    - 13. Corner State and North University. Octagonal house behind trees on the left (Box 6)
    - 14. Turning sod for the Engineering Arch (Box 6)
    - 15. First Ward School, 1872. Professor Ten Brook in foreground. Later sold to U-M and called West Hall. Torn down for Helen Newberry or Betsy Barbour (Box 6)
    - 16. Hale and Smith Bank (Box 6)
    - 17. First National Bank, Main Street circa 1886 (Box 6)
    - 18. NW corner of Main and Washington, built 1836 (Box 6)
    - 19. NW corner Main and Washington 1886 (Box 6)
    - 20. NW corner Main and Washington circa 1896 St. James sold to Bertha Muehlig (Box 6)
    - 21. Hangsterfer Block (built 1860) 1890 (SW Main and Washington). (Box 6)
    - 22. SW corner of Main and Huron circa 1840 (Box 6)
    - 23. Main Street looking north from Washington 1872 (Box 6)
    - 24. William Wagner and his store, east side of Main between Huron and Washington 1888 (Box 6)
    - 25. Old Opera House-Athens Theatre, built 1871. Remodeled by Whitney 1907 (Box 6)
    - 26a. Casper Rinsey's Grocery, SE corner Huron and Fourth Avenue circa 1890s (Box 6)
    - 26. Adjacent to Rinseys but much earlier circa 1860 featuring Haller's Jewelry and Drake's Saloon (Box 6)
    - 27. SE corner Huron and Fourth Avenue (Box 6)
    - 28. Washington Street look east from Main (Box 6)
    - 29. Polhemus Livery (Box 6)
    - 30. Unidentified houses (Box 6)
  - Ypsilanti (slides 31-49)
    - 31. C.L. Yost harness shop (Box 6)
    - 32. John Bryan home (Box 6)
    - 33. Octagon House, S. Huron Street, home and office of Dr. Helen W. McAndrew and William McAndrew (Box 6)
    - 34. Electric car no. 1 (Box 6)
    - 35. Birdseye view 1890 (Box 6)
    - 36. Steam Motor Train 1893 before Ypsilanti High School (Box 6)
    - 37. Michigan Central Depot 1870s (Box 6)
    - 38. Ypsilanti City Mill, Cross and Rice Streets (Box 6)
    - 39. Depot business district (Box 6)
    - 40. Panorama 1859 (Box 6)
    - 41. Woolen Mill 1870 (Box 6)
    - 42. Lumber yard of H.R. Scovill & Co. on the Island (Box 6)
    - 43. Huron Mills (Box 6)
    - 44. Congress Street (now Michigan Avenue) Bridge (Box 6)
    - 45. City Water Tower 1893 (Box 6)
    - 46. North Huron Street, west side, first block, with wooden sidewalk (Box 6)
    - 47. Barton House (Box 6)
    - 48. Atlantis Mineral Wells (Box 6)
    - 49. C.F. Smith store (Schad Block and resident, East Michigan, corner of South Park (Box 6)
  - Other Subjects (slides 50-53)
    - 50. Whitmore Lake, Pioneer and Farmers Picnic 1886 (Box 6)
    - 51. Dexter map with business directory undated (Box 6)
    - 52. Rawsonville. Map showing location (Box 6)
    - 53. Washtenaw County map (Box 6)
- Albums
  - Incomplete album without covers. Subjects include:
    - Allen, Giles B. (Box 6)
    - Chapin, Lucy (Box 6)
    - Chapin, Volney (Box 6)
    - Edwards, James (Box 6)
    - Fox, G.W. (Box 6)
    - Hewitt, C.W. (Box 6)
    - Mason, Brainard (Box 6)
    - Mason, John M. (Box 6)
    - Montgomery, P.D. (Box 6)
    - Oakes, James G. (Box 6)
    - Rolf, Joseph W. (Box 6)
    - Taylor, Charles B. (Box 6)
    - Trask, William S. (Box 6)
    - Woodward, W.H. (Box 6)
  - Album no. 1; subjects include:
    - Chapin, Lucy E. (Box 6)
    - Chapin, Mary F. (Box 6)
    - Chapin, Volney A. (Box 6)
    - Kingsley, Frank (Box 6)
    - Morris, L. (Box 6)
    - Morris, Mrs. L. (Box 6)
    - Red Riding Hood ? (Box 6)
    - Unidentified baby (Box 6)
    - Unidentified girl (Box 6)
    - Unidentified man (Box 6)
  - Album no 2; subject include:
    - Beck, Fred (tintype) (Box 7)
    - Cady ?, Mary Jane (tintype) (Box 7)
    - Davies, May (Box 7)
    - Eureka Concerto Organ (Box 7)
    - Execution scene (Box 7)
    - Steamboat scene (Box 7)
    - Unidentified portraits made in Michigan and Ohio, 30 items (Box 7)
    - Unidentified tintype of couple (Box 7)
  - Album no 3; subjects include:
    - The Nightingale (playing cards) (Box 7)
    - Nydia (sculpture) (Box 7)
    - Traver, Julia (Box 7)
    - Valkyri (Box 7)
    - Wilkins, Molly (actress) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified tintypes, 5 items (Box 7)
    - Unidentified portraits made in Michigan and Ohio, 27 items (Box 7)
  - Album no. 4 (belonged to Captain Seymour Howell); subjects include members of the 6th Michigan Heavy Artillery (i.e. 6th Michigan Infantry)
    (see microfilm of Seymour Howell papers, separately cataloged)
    - Major General B.F. Butler (missing) (Box 7)
    - Beals, Warren (Box 7)
    - Brainard, James (Box 7)
    - Burgess, W.H. (Box 7)
    - Chade, Milton (Box 7)
    - Clark, Frederick (Box 7)
    - Cogswell, Sylvester (Box 7)
    - Corden, John (Box 7)
    - Cummings, Horace (Box 7)
    - Davis, Charles (Box 7)
    - Dickenson, Chester S. (Box 7)
    - Doy, Alfred (Box 7)
    - Ellis, A.I. (Box 7)
    - Fox, S. (Box 7)
    - Hill, T.B. (Box 7)
    - McIlvain, W.W. (Box 7)
    - Montgomery, P.D. (Box 7)
    - Sha...., Gospel Steward W.H. (Box 7)
    - Shepley, Brigadier General (Military Governor of Louisiana) (Box 7)
    - Shumeray, Alonzo (Box 7)
    - Smith, George H. (Box 7)
    - Stone, C.W. (Box 7)
    - Thayer, R.R. (Box 7)
    - Trask, Williams S. (Box 7)
  - Album no. 5 (partially filled with eight unidentified portraits of men, five of women, three of children, and three of groups) (Box 7)
  - Album no. 6; subjects include:
    - Bucklin, Millie (Box 7)
    - Howard, L.C. (Box 7)
    - White, Sarah Ann (Box 7)
    - Sixteen unidentified portraits of women, ten of men, six of children, two group photos (one of them a tintype) (Box 7)
  - Album no. 7; subjects include:
    - De.....?, Janice (Box 7)
    - Falk, Sarah (Box 7)
    - Gildersleve, Inlyza (Box 7)
    - Harrell, Samuel, with Samuel Runnel Harrell (age 2) and Hahnemann Vass Harrell (age 4-1/2) (Box 7)
    - Harris, George (Box 7)
    - Moore, Bessie (Box 7)
    - Porter, May (Box 7)
    - Scanlan, Isabelle (Box 7)
    - Skellenger, Sarah (Box 7)
    - White, David George (Box 7)
    - White, Edward William (Box 7)
    - Witten, Satie (Box 7)
    - Seven unidentified portraits of women, two of men, five of children, and four of groups (Box 7)
  - Album no. 8; subjects include:
    - Catafalque (Box 7)
    - Informal shot of baby in high chair (Box 7)
    - Informal shot of woman in kitchen (Box 7)
    - Unidentified portraits of seventeen women, eight men, six children, and nine groups, most taken in Ann Arbor or Ohio (Box 7)
  - Album no. 9 (empty) (Box 7)
  - Album no. 10
    - University of Michigan class of 1878 album maintained by Jay J. Read
      (volume has been transferred to class album collection)
- Miscellaneous and Oversize
  - Photographs: include Ann Arbor buildings, mills, and organizations; Lapeer County women's group presenting flags to Civil War veterans groups 1883; Ann Arbor newsboys, 1892; Ann Arbor postal workers, circa 1890s (Box 8)
  - Painting of Washtenaw County scene (Box 8)
  - Maps (include maps of Washtenaw Historical Society tours) (Box 8)
  - Forest Hill Cemetery plan (Box 8)
  - Civil War records
    - Michigan Artillery, 6th Regiment, Co. C. (Box 8)
    - Michigan Infantry, 4th Regiment, Co. D. (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous (include printed matter) (Box 8)